module 8 how to price I do want to go back and talk a little bit more about
the customer journey right specifically for service-based businesses let's do
this let's go here let's go here let's go with I need I'm gonna stick with a
lawyer in San Diego just so you kind of understand and can see a little bit more
right you don't necessarily know I didn't specify right what kind of lawyer
I need but look these two individuals have five star reviews 4.3 this is
sponsored lawyers right sponsored fill-in service here in place it's
important why is it important because these people are paying Google to be the
top of your sponsored lawyers search results again here sponsored results
sorry these are sponsored law firms right this is going to be an online attorney
this is going to be lawyers in San Diego these are going to be organic results
the difference here is these firms as well as this I don't know what it is if
it's like an intermediary service or what they're all paying Google to be right
here at the top of your search results here's an organic listing best lawyers in
San Diego these are more directories right so as an example for your business
whatever it is I want you to insert your business right what and think like what
our customers typing in to the search bar to find me where our customers finding
me where our customers finding my competitors okay Google Maps here's a
here's a bunch more but didn't mean to zoom out that much here are a bunch of more
choices right and here's a sponsored Google Maps and I think that's the same
as the other one right Wilshire law firm Wilshire law firm right just as a side
now okay cool continuing on how to price when you're just starting common pricing
traps hourly pay that is the way to sell your time for money and we want to avoid
that from building our business right and sure there are aspects that can be priced for hourly
wage sure however you don't really want to gear your pricing that way well we can
talk about why but it should kind of be common sense custom quotes too early you don't want to
build custom tools for every single one of your customers right you want this repeatable to as many
different niche individuals as possible free pilot this is you can try on our service for three weeks
what does that mean what do they get what do they experience what are you limiting yourself with what
are those guardrails we talked about and then stating price before value that you will always
have that customer that is just tell me how much it is just tell me how much it is just tell me how
much it is you might have to give in or you might just keep I don't even want to say skirting
hammering the value that you are giving problem value right and if they if you can get ahead of
their future problems that they don't even know about you will gain so much more traction in your sales
journey it'll lessen the time from lead to sale right so stating price before value not exactly the
best it's not uh the best frame of mind frame of sale frame of business to come from choose us because
we're cheaper it might be your defining differentiation eventually right now i wouldn't necessarily
start that way here's some pricing models you can choose from flat fee tiered packages intro package
always choose tiered package for right now this is just standard at this point good is your minimum
package i know if you pay i guess the least amount for our services this is exactly what you get
in the middle you might get some scope creep you might get some um account managers or maybe you're doing
yourself performing under right in the middle there difficult to manage it's not a bad thing but it's part
of the business as well as your golden maximum platinum package your best package this is for
individuals that understand the problem by individuals in this instance i mean customers
understand the problem you explain the service perfectly well and they want this done quickly
right and so you're going to incentivize them to pay more for more than likely your attention your
white glove service your best case scenario that you've learned across your business journey that's your
golden or best package here it's simple it's repeatable for all instances right anchoring strategies
um take a look through this this is just some more anecdotal uh anecdotal kind of help here
introduction to value-based pricing tie price to impact and speed not hours again that's that
when you purchase the platinum package we are answering um every phone call that you have any time of day
this is um you get direct access to our ai chat bot right they have customer service at their fingertips
um the 10x roi mental model if your service solves a ten thousand dollar problem a thousand dollar price
tag feels like a bargain so if you
and i like this last part as well frame your price against the cost of their inaction um i'm gonna
stick with the website service for now um if your service is i build websites you shouldn't lead
with i build websites it is i help your customer choose you right and that
scales out to you getting more customers
um that is just the way to frame it right um they now have that i mean you could say ten thousand
dollar problem there you could say hundred thousand dollar problem there depending on how many impressions
they're already getting um maximize that value at the forefront always start simple and always
decouple income from time right stay away from that stop here define your packages for your use case your
business fill it out literally always good to just go through these exercises and we'll go through all of
this in more detail in further courses and here the key takeaways on to the next module